Eleutelcio Bruno Afonso Fernandes

Junior Full Stack Software Developer

Leeds, West Yorkshire 07587 696 045

brunoaf1523@gmail.com

https://github.com/brunoFernandes21



https://www.linkedin.com/in/bruno-fernandes-879b0725a/

PROFILE

I am a very motivated and positive person and I work hard to achieve my objectives. I am passionate about learning and helping others. After my experience at the university of Leeds, I decided to teach myself Web Development so that I could potentially get into the industry. I chose Northcoders because I believed that based on their outstanding reputation and success, they would equip me with all the knowledge and skills I needed to have in order to kick start my career as a Software Developer. I love working in a team environment where I can learn from others and contribute to the success of the team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Language: JavaScript

Front End: HTML5, CSS, CSS Frameworks (Bootstrap, Tailwind, Sass), React, Next, Vue

Back End: Express, Firebase, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, API development, Unit testing

Testing: Jest

Other: Git, Chrome Dev Tools, Web application deployment, Problem solving

OTHER RELEVANT SKILLS

Teamwork, Planning, Research, Time management, Organisation, Self-motivation and enthusiasm, Video editing, Photo editing, Social media content creation.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Click the link to check out all my projects including my Developer Portfolio https://brunofer-projects.netlify.app/

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Trainee Developer Northcoders 15/05/2023 - 15/08/2023

Northcoders is a very well known Tech school in the UK that specializes in transforming people's lives by providing excellent coding bootcamps to aspiring Developers. Their coding school offers courses for absolute beginners and junior software developers to help them kick-start and advance their coding careers.

Course: **Software Development Bootcamp** - The course covers a mixture of back-end and front-end with a focus on building web applications. The main objective is to teach the skills students need to become Software Developers.

- Successfully built and deployed an API (Application Programming Interface)
- Applied all the knowledge acquired to create a fully functional Server and Database
- Solidified my knowledge and understanding of JavaScript fundamentals
- Learned a new testing framework named jest for backend testing

Front End Project: https://www.bfnc-news.com/

Back End Project: https://brunofernandes-northcoders-news.onrender.com/api
Final Project (Group Project): https://books-buzz-app.netlify.app/landing-page

Customer Assistant Waitrose and Partners 18/11/2020 - Present

- Provide excellent customer service to our customers
- Stock and replace products to avoid any damages
- Keep shelves fully stocked with fresh products
- Achieve daily tasks by following procedures

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

Applied Computer Science University of Leeds 04/09/2016 - 28/06/2018

Key Modules: Professional Computing, Software Engineering, Algorithms, Artificial Intelligence, Databases, Operating Systems, Networks, Mathematics.

Projects:

Sorting algorithms; Web development (Creation of websites and web applications); Binary tree, Creation of a command-line shell, Creation of user interface using C++, Software development (group project).

Programming languages learned: Java; C; C++; Python;

Web Programming: HTML; CSS; Flask.

Systems used: Gitlab, IntelliJ IDEA for Java Development. Linux.